<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on discord.py Bot Tutorial</title><link>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on discord.py Bot Tutorial</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:05:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Allowed Mentions</title><link>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/mentions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:05:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/mentions/</guid><description>In this bonus section I'll cover the Discord feature of allowed mentions.
First, what are allowed mentions? Allowed mentions are a way of telling Discord that you don't want to ping for certain mentions in your message. The different types of ping a message can have are @role pings, @everyone or @here pings, @user pings, and reply pings, all of which we can turn on and off pings for when mentioning.</description></item><item><title>Client vs Bot</title><link>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/clientbot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:05:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/clientbot/</guid><description>I often see a lot of people using the wrong one, so here's a guide for which you should use.
discord.Client The Client class is made specifically to connect to the gateway and handle API requests. As such it's not suitable for the majority of bot applications, and using commands.Bot is preferable since it will handle command parsing, permssion checks, etc for you.
discord.ext.commands.Bot The Bot class is designed specifically for you to create functional bots with.</description></item><item><title>Tokens</title><link>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/tokens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:05:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vcokltfre.dev/tips/tokens/</guid><description>In this bonus section I'll explain the 3 most common methods of storing the token for your bot. Note that for these examples you should assume that there is a bot defined somewhere else in the code, and the line bot.run(token) is at the bottom. I won't show the bot code in each example to show just the necessary information, and make this applicable outside of Discord bots too.
You should also be sure when using git to gitignore all of the files you store sensitive information in from any of these examples, to avoide committing them to version control.</description></item></channel></rss>